（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
Even within that brilliant history,
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
Despite being relatively unknown
and lacking a game record,
にもかかわらず—
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
幻のシックスマンがいた と
A phantom sixth man.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Translation Check   AMS
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Dakara itta janai ka
Didn’t I already tell you?
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
Yowasa wo uri ni shitatte
That even if you use your weakness as a selling point.
Timing       sangofe
Mae ni nanka susume ya shinaindaze
You won’t progress at all.
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
Nee hakanai jibun
Hey, my ephemeral self.
Enshutsu shitatte dare mo mukandou
Even if I produce, nobody'll care.
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
Kodoku ga sainamu yoru ni datte
Even on nights when I’m tormented by my loneliness,
Karaokes      KmE
Asu machi wabiru hikari ga aru
there’s a light that’s impatiently waiting for tomorrow.
Tsuyogaru yowai jibun wo mitomerareru tsuyosa wo
I’m weak and just putting up a strong front, but I will start
Hajimerunda yareru mon sa
gathering the strength I need to admit that I can do it.
Soko kara mae wo mui chatte
From there, I’ll look straight ahead.
Aruke
And I’ll walk,
Hashire
I’ll run,
nando demo
no matter how many times it takes.
Choushi hazure no koe datte ii sa
Doesn’t matter if I’m out of tune.
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Sore ga doushitan datte
What’s wrong with that?
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
Encoding      Your Mom
Sakebunda ore no ban da can you do it?
Now shout, it’s my turn, can you do it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Suru to dou darou nan datte
When I do it, how’s that?
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Kowaku nanka naku natten ze
Somehow my fears are all gone.
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Kyou ga wagami da
It’s my day today...
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
I
can
do
it
You
can
do
it
We
can
do
it
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
Seirin
Kaijo
（日向(ひゅうが)）全員 気ぃ入れろ
Seirin
Kaijo
Give it your all, everyone.
こっから試合終了まで
第１クオーターと同じ—
This'll be just like the first quarter from here on out.
点の取り合い…
ランガン勝負だ！！
A back and forth run-and-gun game!
（黒子(くろこ)）あっ…！
（黄瀬(きせ)）ぬおおお！
オレは負けねえっスよ 誰にも
I won't lose.
Not to anyone.
黒子っちにも
Not even Kurokocchi.
Kagami...
（黒子）火神(かがみ)君
（火神）はっ！
ここを取れれば—
If we can get the ball,
黄瀬君に コピーされない手が
もう１つあります
there's one more thing we can do that Kise can't copy.
１回きりの
単純な手ですけど…
It's a simple strategy that will only work once though.
（日向）どあ〜っ！
（笠松(かさまつ)）抜かせるな！！
Don't let them through!
（火神）黒子！
Kuroko!
He shot it?
（黄瀬）シュート！？
No...
…じゃねえ！
It's an alley-oop!
アリウープだ！！
This ends now!
（火神）
これで 終わりだからな！！
Episode 5
Your Basketball
（火神）でやっ ハァ ハァ
ハァ…
Seirin
Kaijo
（海常(かいじょう)部員たちのどよめき）
All right!
うおっしゃあああ！
ふははっ！ うれしい通り越して
信じらんねえ
I can't believe we won.
ハァ ハァ…
I lost?
負け… たんスか…？
（黄瀬）生まれて 初めて…
For the first time in my life, I...
負(ま)っ…
Huh? What?
あれ…？
あれ？
Is Kise crying?
（海常部員１）黄瀬 泣いてねえ？
I know he must be frustrated, but...
（海常部員２）いやあ
悔しいのは 分かっけど…
（海常部員３）
練習試合だろ たかが
It's just a practice game.
You idiot!
（笠松）このボケッ！
（黄瀬）どわあ！ って…
Stop crying.
（笠松）メソメソしてんじゃねーよ
And you've got some balls to say you've never lost before.
つーか 今まで
負けたことがねえってほうが—
ナメてんだよ
シバくぞ！
I'll hit you!
そのスッカスカの辞書に
ちゃんと—
You'd better add the word
"revenge" to that empty dictionary of yours!
“リベンジ”って単語
追加しとけ！
（ホイッスル）
（審判）整列！
Line up.
With a score of 100-98, Seirin High wins.
100 対 98で
誠凛高校の勝ち！
（選手たち）
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much.
Because we're in different districts,
地区 違うから 次やるとしたら
インターハイ 本番っスね
if we play again, it'll be at the Inter-High.
（リコ）ん〜
（日向）絶対 行きます！
We'll be there.
I don't want to confess my love buck-naked.
全裸でコクるの ヤだし
あはっ！
Let's go!
（日向）おし！ 行くぞ！
Yes, sir!
（誠凛部員たち）はい！
Hey, where's Kise?
（海常部員）おい 黄瀬は？
（黒子）ん？
Gemini's horoscope predicted
（緑間(みどりま)）オマエの 双子座は
今日の運勢 最悪だったのだが—
terrible luck for you today,
but I didn't think you'd actually lose.
まさか負けるとは
思わなかったのだよ
You came to watch, Midorimacchi?
見にきてたんスか
緑間っち
まっ どちらが勝っても
不快な試合だったが
Either way, it was an unfortunate game.
サルでもできる ダンクの応酬
Even a monkey could have managed those dunks.
It's no wonder fate didn't choose your side.
運命に選ばれるはずもない
I haven't seen you since middle school.
中学以来っスね お久しぶりっス
It's good to see you again.
I see you haven't stopped taping your fingers.
テーピングも相変わらずっスね
Anyway, who cares if I dunk as long as it goes in?
つーか 別に ダンクでも
何でもいいじゃないスか 入れば
That's why you're no good.
だからオマエは ダメなのだよ
近くからは 入れて当然
Getting the ball in from up close is easy.
シュートは遠くから決めてこそ
価値があるのだ
Getting it in from distance has true value.
Didn't anyone teach you to
"do everything you can and God will do the rest"?
“人事を尽くして 天命を待つ”
という言葉を 習わなかったか？
Optimal effort makes you worthy of fate's grace.
まず 最善の努力
そこから初めて 運命に
選ばれる資格を得るのだよ
オレは人事を尽くしている
そして—
I always do everything I can, and I always keep the Oha-Asa horoscope's lucky item on me.
おは朝占いの
ラッキーアイテムは—
必ず 身につけている
By the way, today's item is a toy frog.
ちなみに今日は
カエルのオモチャだ
That is why my shots never miss.
だからオレのシュートは 落ちん
（黄瀬）んあ…
毎回 思うんスけど—
I've never understood that last part.
最後の意味が 分からん
This is the Generation of Miracles' number one shooter.
これが“キセキの世代”
ナンバーワン シューター
Shouldn't you be talking to Kurokocchi instead of me?
（黄瀬）つーか オレより
黒子っちと話さなくていいんスか？
必要ない
There's no need.
Ｂ型のオレとＡ型のあいつは
相性が最悪なのだよ
B-blood types like myself and A-blood types like him never get along.
I not only acknowledge his style, but respect it.
あいつのスタイルは
認めているし—
むしろ 尊敬すらしている
だが—
Yet I cannot accept his decision to attend an obscure school like Seirin.
誠凛などと 無名の新設校へ
行ったのは いただけない
ただ 地区予選で当たるので
来てみたが—
I simply came because we'll play them in the division preliminaries.
正直 話にならないな
But honestly, they're not good enough.
（高尾(たかお)）緑間 テメエ！
Midorima, you bastard!
渋滞で つかまったら
１人で先 行きやがって
You left me alone in the middle of traffic!
なんか超 恥ずかしいだろうが！！
Do you know how embarrassing that is?!
まあ 今日は試合を見にきただけだ
I just came to watch the game today.
だが 先に謝っておくよ
But allow me to apologize.
There is no way we will lose to Seirin.
オレたちが誠凛に負けるという
運命は あり得ない
I regret to tell you that you should give up on your revenge.
残念だが リベンジは
諦めたほうがいい
Sasaki General Hospital
Everything's okay.
異常なし！
That's great.
よかったなあ
Sorry for worrying you.
（黒子）ご心配おかけしました
I didn't know what would happen when you fell over.
（伊月(いづき)）倒れたときは
どうなるかと思ったぜ
I'm just glad you're all right.
（土田(つちだ)）まぁ 何はともあれ
（小金井(こがねい)）んっ ひひっ！
っしゃあああ 勝ったあ！！
（部員たちの歓声）
All right! We won!
Let's get something to eat on the way home.
帰り どっかで食べてこーぜ
あ〜 何にする？
What do you want?
安いもんで オレ 金ねえ〜
Something cheap. I'm broke.
（火神）オレも
（黒子）ボクも
Me too.
So am I.
Hold on.
ちょい 待ち
（リコ）今 全員の所持金
交通費抜いて いくら？
How much does everyone have after transportation costs?
Let's go home.
帰ろっか…
Yeah.
Free Steak
It's okay. What do you say we go for steak?
大丈夫！ むしろ
ガッツリ いこうか 肉！！
Super Volume
Kg
Super Awesome
Super Delish
STEAK
DiG IN!!
OMG me wants!
If you eat it all within 30 minutes, it's free!!
If you fail to, you must pay 10,000 yen.
What's wrong? Don't hold back.
どしたの？ 遠慮せず
いっちゃって
This is too much!
（部員たち）
ガッツリ いきすぎじゃね？
What are we going to do if we can't eat all of this?
マジ これ食えなかったら
どーすんの？
え？ ちょっとお
What?
Why do you think I make you run every day?
何のために毎日
走り込みしてると思ってんの？
（部員たち）バスケのためだよ
It wasn't for basketball?
（日向）はぁ ああいうヤツだと
分かってたはずなのに…
I should know by now that this is how she is.
This steak is steakalicious.
このステーキ ステキ
Sorry, but those jokes are really annoying right now.
ごめん そういうの 今
マジ ウザイ
Excuse me.
（黒子）すみません
（日向）ふ〜 どうした？
Do you need some water?
水か？
I give up.
ギブです
Steak                                             Bomber
Kuroko!
（部員たち）黒子ぉ〜！！
Steak                                             Bomber
（水戸部(みとべ)）うぉ〜
（日向）死んだ…
I'm dead.
（火神）うんめ〜
つか おかわり アリかな？
This is delicious!
Maybe I'll get some more.
Huh? If you're not gonna eat that, can I have it?
あれ？ いらないんだったら
もらっていい？ …ですか？
He's stuffing his cheeks like a squirrel.
（日向）リスみたいに食っとる
Save me the hassle and please bring them all over here.
（火神）面倒っスから 全部
こっち 持ってきてください
（部員たち）おお〜！ 火神！
ありがと〜う！
Steak                                             Bomber
Kagami, thank you!
Recommendations
_
Bigfoot
Sirloin Steak
L
Murakami
Salisbury Steak
L
Southern
French-Style Kebab
L
Open Everyday
黄瀬君
Kise?
ちょっと 話さねえスか？
Do you have a minute to talk?
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Recommendations
_
Bigfoot
Sirloin Steak
L
Murakami
Salisbury Steak
L
Southern
French-Style Kebab
L
Open Everyday
Thanks for the food!
（リコ）ごちそうさまでした〜！
Yeah, don't come back!
（店主）おう 二度と来んな〜！
（火神）うえっ
さすがに食い過ぎた
I think I ate too much.
You really are a monster.
（日向）いやあ オマエ
やっぱ バケモンだな
But you saved us.
（小金井）でも助かったな〜
よし！ じゃあ帰ろっか
全員いる？
Okay, let's go home. Is everyone here?
あれ？ 黒子は？
Where's Kuroko?
I'm sure he's near the back, just like he always...
（伊月）いつものことだろ？
どうせまた 最後尾とかに…
Recommendations
_
Bigfoot
Sirloin Steak
L
Murakami
Salisbury Steak
L
Southern
French-Style Kebab
L
Open Everyday
He's not there.
（部員たち）いない…
It's been a while since we last talked like this.
（黄瀬）てか こうしてちゃんと
話すのも 久しぶりっスね
How's your injury?
ケガ 大丈夫スか？
I'm fine.
はい 大丈夫です
By the way, I saw Midorimacchi.
そういえば
緑間っちに会ったっスよ
正直 あの人は ちょっと苦手です
Honestly, I don't get along with him very well.
（黄瀬）アッハ そういや
そうだったっスねえ
Now that you mention it, you're right.
That left hand of his is no joke though.
けど あの左手は
ハンパねえっスよ 実際
かに座がいい日は 特に
Especially on good days for Cancers.
Yes.
はい
Seems like he just came to watch today's game.
まあ 今日は
見にきただけらしいっスわ
Anyway...
それより—
First you turned me down,
and then I lost today's game.
黒子っちにもフラれ
試合にも負けて—
Everything's going wrong with my life right now.
高校生活 いきなり
踏んだり蹴ったりっスわ
ダメ元でも 一応
マジだったんスよ〜
I didn't expect you to say yes,
but I was serious.
（黒子）ひっくり返りますよ
You'll fall over.
ん… すみません
Sorry.
I'm kidding.
冗談っスよ
そんなことより
話したかったのは—
Anyway, I wanted to ask you for your reason.
理由(わけ)を聞きたかったんスよ
Why, right after the middle school championship game,
なんで 全中の試合が
終わったとたん—
did you disappear?
姿を消したんスか？
I can't believe no one noticed him leave.
（リコ）まったく 誰も
気付かないなんて—
I know he's got no presence, but this is ridiculous.
影 薄いにも程があるわぁ
Doesn't Kuroko have a phone?
黒子〜 あいつ
ケータイ持ってねーのかよお
I can't believe he just disappeared like that.
てか すぐ フラフラ
どっか消えるって 子犬か
What is he, a puppy?
Let's just hurry up and find him.
それより 早く見つけましょう
Maybe I'll put him in a
Boston crab hold when we do.
逆エビの刑は それからかな
Sheesh.
ったく…
（学生１）
おいほら こっちこっち
Hey, over here!
（学生２）ふっ へへへへ
（学生３）おいこっち パス パス！
Pass me the ball!
（学生１）へいへい！
Street ball.
（火神）ストリートかあ
It's been a while since I've seen that in Japan.
日本じゃ 久しぶりに見るな
ん… 分かりません
I'm not sure.
What?
It's true I began to question Teiko's policies because of the championship game.
（黒子）帝光の方針に
疑問を感じたのは—
確かに 決勝戦が原因です
あのとき ボクは 何かが
欠落していると思った
I felt we lacked something.
スポーツなんて
勝って なんぼじゃないスか
Sports are all about winning.
それより大切なことなんて
あるんスか？
What could be more important?
Over here!
I thought the same thing until recently.
（黒子）ボクもこの前まで
そう思っていました
So I still don't know exactly what's wrong with it,
だから 何がいけないかは
まだ ハッキリ分からないです
but...
ただ—
all I know is I hated basketball at that time.
ボクはあの頃 バスケが嫌いだった
The feel of the ball.
ボールの感触
バッシュのスキール音
The squeak of basketball shoes.
ネットをくぐる音…
The swish of the net.
I started playing because I loved the game.
ただ 好きで始めた
バスケなのに…
That's why I was so impressed when I met Kagami.
だから火神君に会って
ホントにすごいと思いました
He loves basketball from the bottom of his heart.
心の底から
バスケットが好きで—
He seems to have been through rough times,
ちょっと怖いときや—
クサったときも
あったみたいだけど—
全部 人一倍 バスケに対して
真剣だからだと思います
but he still takes basketball more seriously
than anyone else.
分かんねえっスわ
I don't get it.
けど １つ言えるのは—
I can say one thing though.
If you think so highly of Kagami because of his attitude towards basketball,
黒子っちが火神を買う理由が
バスケへの姿勢だとしたら…
some day the two of you...
（黄瀬）
黒子っちと 火神は いつか—
will part ways.
決別するっスよ
The biggest difference between me and
オレと４人との決定的な違い
the other four isn't our physical abilities.
それは身体能力なんかじゃなく—
誰にも オレにも
マネできない才能を—
They all have a special ability not even I can imitate.
それぞれ 持ってるってことっス
I realized during today's game that he's still learning.
今日の試合で分かったんス
あいつはまだ 発展途上
そして“キセキの世代”と同じ—
Just like the Generation of Miracles,
he has a unique ability.
オンリーワンの才能を秘めてる
For now, he's still an immature challenger.
今は 未完成の挑戦者っス
ただ ガムシャラにプレーして
強敵と戦うことを—
He's enjoying the thrill of recklessly playing strong opponents.
楽しんでいるだけのね
However,
けど いつか必ず—
someday he will achieve the level of the Generation of Miracles
“キセキの世代”と
同格に成長して—
チームから浮いた存在になる
and grow apart from his team.
When he does, do you really believe
そのとき 火神は 今と
変わらないで いられるんスかね？
Kagami won't be a different person?
You bastard, why'd you disappear like that?
（火神）テメエ 何 フラフラ
消えてんだよ
よう
Hey.
Were you listening?
聞いてたんスか？
I sure as hell was.
（火神）“聞いてた”じゃねえよ
What the hell are you kidnapping Kuroko for?
オマエ 何 いきなり
黒子 拉致ってんの？
What? Who cares if I talk with him a little bit?
はあ？ ちょっとくらい
いいじゃないスか
We can't go home.
（火神）帰れねぇんだよ
The coach won't shut up about responsibility or something.
カントクが 責任あるって
うるさくてよ
（平野）んだよ クソ
うじゃうじゃいんじゃん
Damn it, looks like there's some trash over here.
We've been looking for him.
みんなで捜してたんだよ
Come on, you've had enough.
（平野）オラア もう十分
遊んだろ？ 代われ 代われ
Give someone else a turn.
We just got here. Wait your turn.
（学生１）こっちだって
来たばっかだよ 順番…
（大垣）はあ！？ 順番？
Our turn?
Now, now.
（板崎）まあまあ ここはホラ
バスケで決めるとか どう？
Why don't we settle this with some basketball?
Who are those thugs?
何だ あいつら ガラワリイな
へっ よっしゃあ！
All right!
Wow, not bad. We might lose.
あれ〜 やるねえ
負けちゃう〜？
（学生）んあ… くっ…
（板崎）せいっ！
（学生１）く… よっし！
This is it!
（学生１）これで…
（平野）はい ブロ〜ック！
And block!
（学生１）くっ… ちょっ…
Huh? Hey, what was that?
何だよ 今の
スリーオンスリーだろ
It's three-on-three!
What?
（坂崎）はあい？
バスケでっつったろ？
I said we'd play basketball.
スリーオンスリーなんて
一言も言ってねえし
I didn't say anything about three-on-three.
What are you saying?
（学生１）何だよ それ！
んな卑怯(ひきょう)な…
That's not fair!
（板崎）でぇぃ！
（学生１）あっ…！
（板崎）え？ 何て？
（学生１）あっ… うぅ…
Huh? What'd you say?
Sorry, I didn't hear you.
ワリィ よく聞こえなかったわ
There's nothing fair about this.
どう見ても 卑怯です
ぬあっ！ 熱っ！
Who the hell are you? Where'd you come from?
てか 何だ テメエ！
どっから湧いた？
そんなバスケは ないと思います
This isn't basketball.
Besides, violence is bad.
何より 暴力はダメです
What the hell is he doing?
（火神）な〜にを やっとんじゃ〜
Kurokocchi?
（黄瀬）黒子っち〜！！
はああ？ いきなり何だ テメエ
What do you think you're doing?
（坂崎）フハハハ
いんだね 今どき
There are still guys like this these days.
Fine, then.
いいぜ 別に
じゃあ バスケで勝負してやるよ
Let's settle this with basketball.
って…
Mind if we play too?
（黄瀬）あの〜 オレらも
混ざっていいスか？
Why'd you get involved, bastard?
つーか 何 いきなり
かましてんだ テメエ
H-He's huge!
（明常(めいじょう)部員たち）
でででで でけえ…！
なんじゃ〜！？
What the hell?
（火神）５対３でいいぜ
かかってこいよ
Five-on-three's fine. Bring it on.
What'd you say?!
（板崎）何だとお！
They destroyed them.
（明常部員たち）瞬殺…
（学生たち）すっげえ…
Amazing!
What were you thinking?!
オマエは 何を考えてんだ！
あのままケンカになったら
勝てるつもりだったのかよお
Did you think you could win if it turned into a fight?!
No, they would have beaten me up.
いや 100パーセント
ボコボコにされてました
You bastard!
テッメ…
Look at these guns.
見てください この 力コブ
You don't have any!
ねえし！
Kurokocchi, you can be amazing sometimes.
黒子っちって
たまに すごいよね
I thought those guys were terrible.
（黒子）それでもあの人たちは
ひどいと思いました
I just wanted to tell them.
だから言っただけです
You should've considered the consequences first!
だから その先を考えろ
I forgot to.
忘れてました
Don't give me that crap!
（火神）
忘れてました じゃねえよ
I'm sorry.
（黒子）すいませんでした
（火神）オマエ自分でも 100パー
ボコられるって言ってたろ
You said yourself they could beat you up!
（黄瀬）フッ
（黒子）すいませんでした…
Sorry.
I should get going.
じゃあ オレは
そろそろ行くっスわ
最後に黒子っちと一緒に
プレーできたしね
I finally got to play with you, Kurokocchi.
あと 火神っちにも
リベンジ 忘れてねえっスよ！
And don't think I've forgotten about my revenge, Kagamicchi!
"K-Kagamicchi"?!
（火神）か… 火神っち！？
Kise adds "-cchi" to the names of those he acknowledges.
黄瀬君は 認めた人には
“なになにっち”をつけます
よかったですね
That's great for you.
（火神）やだけど！！
I don't want that!
（黄瀬）予選で負けんなよ！
Don't lose in the preliminaries!
Kagami, I'd like to ask you something.
火神君 １つだけ聞かせてください
Did you hear my conversation with Kise?
あの話を聞いてましたか？
決別するとか しないとか？
About us parting ways?
We don't even get along in the first place.
ていうか それ以前にオレ—
オマエと 気ぃ合ってねえし
１人じゃ無理だって言ったのは
オメエだろ
You're the one who said I couldn't do it alone.
If you're right, there's nothing to worry about.
だったら いらねえ心配すんな
Besides...
それに—
You'll always stand by the light.
いつも光とともにある—
That's your basketball.
それがオマエのバスケだろ？
Kagami, that was pretty deep.
（黒子）火神君も結構 言いますね
Shut up!
（火神）うるせえよ！
（リコ）
くっ うう あっ！ いた！！
There you are! Geez!
もう！！ でいっ！
（リコ）うぐ… きっ…
（黒子）あ… い…
All right, let's go home.
（日向）よーし 帰るぞ〜
（黒子）か… 火神君…
K-Kagami...
Save... Save me...
たっ… 助け…
だって悔しくて まじ情けなくて
datte kuyashikute maji nasakenakute
It's frustrating, it's really shameful.
止まらない涙を笑いたきゃ笑え
tomaranai namida wo waraitakya warae
If you want to laugh at my unstoppable tears, go ahead and laugh.
不公平すぎだろ 生まれつき違うんだ
fukouheisugi daro umaretsuki chigaunda
Isn't it too unfair? We're different the moment we're born.
遠くなる背中を指くわえて見てる
tooku naru senaka wo yubi kuwaete miteru
I can only look enviously at your back getting further away.
「天才なんだよ」追いつけやしない
"tensai nanda yo" oitsuke ya shinai
"You're a genius", there's no way I can catch up.
自分の限界値を勝手に決めてた
jibun no genkaichi wo katte ni kimeteta
I willfully set my limits on myself.
本当は知ってる 本当のことを
hontou wa shitteru hontou no koto wo
I really know it, I know the truth.
誰より努力してる姿
dare yori doryoku shiteru sugata
I know I worked harder than anyone else.
見えないふりしてんのは
mienai furi shiten no wa
I'm just pretending to not see it.
わかってるんだ わかってるんだ だけど
wakatterunda wakatterunda dakedo
I know it, I know it, but...
どうにもこうにもなんないからとか
dou ni mo kou ni mo nannai kara to ka
I say it won't work or be like this and
なんとかかんとか言って
nantoka kantoka yutte
so and so and so on.
みんなも自分も自分も自分も
minna mo jibun mo jibun mo jibun mo
Fooling everyone and myself and myself
上手にだまくらかして
jouzu ni damakurakashite
and myself skillfully.
一体全体僕は何を誇れるだろう
ittaizentai boku wa nani wo hokoreru darou
What in the world can I be proud of?
あの日のボクは僕を嗤うかな
ano hi no boku wa boku wo warau ka na
Will that me someday laugh at the me right now?
もっと もっと 空は碧いはずさ
motto motto sora wa aoi hazu sa
The sky is supposed to be much much bluer.
Now, start it right away!!
Next Episode
（小金井）水戸部
何 落ち込んでんだよ
Mitobe, what's got you down?
What? You're worried about the first years?
１年が心配？
大丈夫 パン 買うだけじゃん
It'll be fine. We're just buying some bread.
（小金井）なあ つっちー？
（土田）あ… ああ
Right, Tsucchi?
Um, yeah.
なんで 会話が成り立つんだろう…
How was that a conversation?
Episode 6
Let Me Tell You Two Things